{"test_questions": [[{"question": "According to the recommendations of International Navigational Congress in 1912, the ratio of length to width at the entrance for cargo vessels is", "opta": "5.5 and 6.0 to 1", "optb": "6.2 and 6.8 to 1", "optc": "7.4 and 7.8 to 1", "optd": "8.2 and 8.5 to 1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "An artificial barrier which makes the enclosed area safe for anchorage of ships, is known as break water", "optb": "The break water whose inside is used as a plateform for loading and unloading is called a mole", "optc": "The length of the quay wall is governed by the length of the largest vessel likely to be berthed", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Buoys which support the cables to which vessels are attached are of", "opta": "cylindrical shape", "optb": "drum", "optc": "pear shaped", "optd": "spherical shape", "opte": "all of these.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The beach is built:", "opta": "with largest material locally available to the waves", "optb": "with large material locally available to the waves", "optc": "with fine material locally available to the waves", "optd": "with finest material locally available to the waves.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Flow of air from one place to the other is caused due to", "opta": "the sum of elevation", "optb": "pressure head", "optc": "velocity head", "optd": "all of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "For nautical purposes, low water level is generally referred to by the navigators", "optb": "The depth of the bed of the sea from the surface of water is called sounding", "optc": "The contour lines on the bed of a water body are called fathoms", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The direction of the littoral drift depends upon the direction of the wave with respect to the coastline", "optb": "The direction of a river opening to the sea determines the direction of no littoral drift", "optc": "Harbour in the path of littoral drift is not constructed to avoid a build up of sand on one side and erosion on the other", "optd": "all of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A low wall built out into the sea more or less perpendicular to the coast line, to resist the travel of sand and shingle along a beach, is called", "opta": "break water", "optb": "break wall", "optc": "groins", "optd": "shore wall.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At a place the shore line is along North West-South East. The wind is blowing from the north. The littoral drift will be along", "opta": "south east", "optb": "south", "optc": "south west", "optd": "west", "opte": "north west", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If F is the fetch, the straight line distance of open water available in kilometres, the height of the wave in metres is", "opta": "0.15 F", "optb": "0.20 F", "optc": "0.28 F", "optd": "0.34 F", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to the recommendations of International Navigational Congress in 1912, the ratio of length to width at the entrance for passenger vessels is :", "opta": "7.25 to 1", "optb": "7.80 to 1", "optc": "8.11 to 1", "optd": "8.44 to 1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The operation of removing material from the sea or river bed is known as", "optb": "Dredging", "optc": "Digging", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Littoral drift", "opta": "is the raised line of sand, parallel to the sea coast", "optb": "is the slow movement of surface water at sea caused by the wind", "optc": "is a current parallel to the shore, caused due to tangential component of the wind", "optd": "is a current perpendicular to the shore line caused due to wind.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The heaviest line is used to democrate", "opta": "the low water line", "optb": "the high water line", "optc": "the limit of swamps", "optd": "the direction of current.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following statements is correct?", "opta": "The soundings are made with respect to the mean low water", "optb": "The soundings which are below the datum are written in black on the map", "optc": "The spot heights of the features above datum are written in red on the map", "optd": "The decimal point of the sounding value is at the exact position of the sounding", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement function following:", "opta": "The coarse material which has a smaller angle of repose, causes a steeper beach slope", "optb": "The coarse material which has a greater angle of repose, causes a steeper beach slope", "optc": "The flattening out of the beach is caused due to the movement of small and uniform particles leeward.", "optd": "both (b) and (c).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The wavelength is computed by Bertin's formula (where T is the period in seconds).", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The regular periodic rise and fall of the surface of the sea, is called tide.", "optb": "The average difference in water level between high tide and low tide at a place, is called tidal range", "optc": "The movement of water caused by the action of tide, is called a tidal current", "optd": "all of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Depth of borings for soil investigation, is generally kept below low water level", "opta": "30 m", "optb": "35 m", "optc": "45 m", "optd": "40 m", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following land marks on the coast line must be depicted on hydrographic maps ?", "opta": "shore line", "optb": "light houses", "optc": "church spires", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A lead line or sounding line", "opta": "is stretched thoroughly when wet before it is graduated", "optb": "should be soaked in water for about one hour prior to taking soundings", "optc": "is adjusted at regular interval", "optd": "is generally used for depths exceeding 6 m", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The smoothened surface of the front face of the guay walls, is known as fending which is made of", "opta": "granite stone", "optb": "timber", "optc": "steel", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The shore line survey includes :", "opta": "depicting the shore line", "optb": "depicting the prominent details on shore line", "optc": "depicting the high water line", "optd": "depicting the low water line", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following statements is not relevant to hydrographic survey :", "opta": "establishment of a chain of bench marks near the shore line", "optb": "establishment of horizontal control points on the shore", "optc": "determination of the sea bed profile", "optd": "depicting the irregularities in the shore line, islands and projecting rocks", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The important component of a sea port is", "opta": "terminal buildings", "optb": "the docks", "optc": "the harbour", "optd": "all of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cretans :", "opta": "are the harbours established on the island south east of Greek mainland", "optb": "are the natives of crete, an island south of Greek mainland", "optc": "are the plants, grown in the neighbourhood of harbours", "optd": "none of the above.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The fixed mooring does not require", "opta": "mooring post", "optb": "bollard", "optc": "anchors", "optd": "capstan.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The low water datum for a lake is defined as the surface of the lake when it is at elevation", "opta": "180.5 m above M.S.L.", "optb": "190.5 m above M.S.L.", "optc": "170.5 m above M.S.L.", "optd": "200.0 m above M.S.L.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "P and Q are two stations on the shore line at distance d. If the angle between Q and the boat O and P is a and the angle between P and Q at boat O is \u03b2, the x and y. Coordinate along PQ and perpendicular to PQ from O are :", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "none of the above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A harbour is a place where", "opta": "ships get shelter and protection against destructive forces due to sea waves", "optb": "facilities are provided for receiving cargo and passengers", "optc": "port buildings are constructed for commercial purposes", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following: In a dry dock block made of hard wood,", "opta": "spacing of the blocks is 1.35 m", "optb": "the lowest block is 1.8 m long 40 cm x 40 cm in cross-section", "optc": "the middle block is 1.6 m long 40 cm x 40 cm in crosss-section", "optd": "the top block is 1.2 m long 40 cm x 40 cm in cross-section", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On a hydrographic map, the following feature is shown :", "opta": "datum", "optb": "high and low water lines", "optc": "depth contours", "optd": "land and water areas", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Due to the impact of water wave on a sea shore structure", "opta": "hydrostatic pressure coupled with a strong momentary impact is caused", "optb": "vibrations are subjected", "optc": "internal pressure is developed", "optd": "weakens the foundation", "opte": "all of the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The horizontal angles from the boat between A and B and B and C, the stations on the shore are respectively \u03b81 and \u03b82. The distances AB = L1 and BC = L2. For calculating the angle \u03b12 at C between the boat and station B is obtained by using the following formula: where (\u03b2 is horizontal angle between A and C at B).", "opta": "", "optb": "\u03b1t tan \u03b12 = 360\u00b0 - (\u03b81 + \u03b82 + \u03b2) = \u03c6", "optc": "", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The breakwater which can be used as a platform for loading and unloading of cargo is called a mole", "optb": "The brick masonry retaining wall which is used for loading and unloading of cargo is called guay wall", "optc": "Three types of break waters are generally provided in harbours", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The dock wall is designed as a gravity retaining wall and is tested for", "opta": "back fill pressure when the dock is empty", "optb": "maximum water pressure from the dock without any back fill", "optc": "the load charge transmitted to the dock by the movement of loaded vehicles or trains on the way", "optd": "all of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The shape of docks and basins is generally kept", "opta": "rectangular ways", "optb": "diamond shape guays", "optc": "inclined gauys", "optd": "all of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Surf zone is :", "opta": "the fathom line of 10 m depth", "optb": "the fathom line of 5 m depth", "optc": "the swell of the sea breaking on the shore or reefs", "optd": "the coast line attacked by the waves.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following lines is used for tying a ship with a dock", "opta": "bow line", "optb": "stern line", "optc": "spring line", "optd": "break line", "opte": "all of these.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Soundings are required for", "opta": "making nautical charts for navigation", "optb": "ascertaining the areas subject to scour or silting", "optc": "obtaining detailed information for construction", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If h and h1 are the heights of a light house and the observer in a ship in metres above M S L then the horizontal distance from the ship to the light house in kilometres is", "opta": "3.86 (h + h1)", "optb": "3.86 (h - h1)", "optc": "3.86 (h x h1)", "optd": "3.86 \u03c0 (h + h1)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The artificial barrier constructed to enclose \"n area for safe anchorage, is called break water", "optb": "The smoothened surface at the top end of the vertical face of a guay wall, is called fending", "optc": "The effective berthing lengths of inclined guays can be adjusted", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For location of soundings a range and one angle from the shore involves the following operations. Which one is correct ?", "opta": "A range line is established", "optb": "The first and the last soundings and every tenth soundings are fixed by angular observations", "optc": "The intermediate soundings are fixed by the time intervals", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "the Mediterranean sea is considered to be a huge harbour", "optb": "the Caspean sea is considered to be a big harbour", "optc": "the Red sea is considered to be harbour", "optd": "none of the above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "a harbour without any port complex, is called a refuge harbour", "optb": "a harbour used for fishery, is called fishery harbour", "optc": "the terminal building of a commercial harbour consists of an administrative block, customs clearance and ware-houses.", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following:", "opta": "As a wave of sea water approaches the coast line, it is generally accompanied by a drift of water in the direction of wave advance", "optb": "The on-shore wind helps to produce wave action as well as rise of M.S.L.", "optc": "A falling hydraulic gradient occurs in the direction of the wave", "optd": "The wave while receding carries finer particles out to deep water.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a wet dock system,", "opta": "minimum required depth of water for the vessels is maintained", "optb": "entrance locks are provided with massive gates", "optc": "the locks of dock gate are operated by means of heavy bascule bridges and connected machinery", "optd": "the cost of construction is quite heavy", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A roadstead :", "opta": "is a protected area of water where boats can move safely", "optb": "is the end of the road at the harbour", "optc": "may be protected by break water walls", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The width of the entrances of the harbours is restricted to", "opta": "100 m", "optb": "125 m", "optc": "150 m", "optd": "180 m", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "The tides at any place occur a little less than 1 hour later, each succeeding day", "optb": "The difference in time in solar hours and minutes from any lunar transit to the succeeding transit, is called high water level", "optc": "The influence of the earth's gravity alone produces level-tidal less sea", "optd": "The spinning force is maximum at the equator and zero at the poles", "opte": "All of the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}